Software Engineer

Contact

- **(**+98) 912-857-0030
- 🔀 farzad.rafieimanesh@gmail.com
- Avesta St., No. 25, 2nd floor, Sheikh Bahai Square, Tehran Iran
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/farzad -rafeemanesh

Education

(1996-2000)

Bachelor of Software Engineering,

Najaf Abad Azad University,

Isfahan Province

Other features

Project Management



Problem-solving

Systems analysis and design



Programming



Working group /communication



English



Profile

My name is Farzad Rafiei Manesh and I was born in September 1977.

After graduating in the field of software engineering from the university in 1379, in the field of analysis - design and production and development of software systems with more than 22 years of experience in Tehran with government organizations such as the Tax Affairs Organization, Tehran Municipality, Judiciary and...(from 2001 to 2018) I also cooperated with software companies such as Naji Research and Development (from 2017 to now) and Bahman Pardaz (from 2021 to now).

In the system analysis and design department, I have mastered methodologies such as RUP and am fully familiar with the Scrum framework.

I am fluent in Java and Delphi programming languages and in the field of database management programming, I am fully familiar with PLSQL in Oracle and also with SQL Server database management system.

I also have valuable experience in the field of user interface design (UI/UX).

During this period, in addition to administrative and management activities, I was also a product owner and project manager, and due to my experience in optimizing processes and work methods, presenting development plans, maintaining and supporting software systems, and leading production and development teams, I achieved many successes.

Also, I am powerful and efficient in understanding and translating the complex requirements of various businesses and turning them into a software product with the desired quality, as well as ensuring its timely delivery based on the schedule developed for the project.

Due to my high spirit in doing group work, I am interested in working in software teams.

Professional Experience

Bahman Pardaz Company (2021 to now)

- Project manager, analyst and designer of the army logistics system (system design for the implementation of general policies in order to provide, procure, purchase and transfer equipment to organizations, as well as maintenance and transportation affairs and management and maintenance of vehicles and equipments)
- Project manager, analyst and designer of the government service desk (designing web services from other systems to serve the people)
- Project manager, analyst and inspection designer of organizations (for the appointment of people in jobs, evaluation, promotion and training of employees in government jobs)

Favorites

Sports (Climbing, Judo and Chess)
Music
Studying historical books
Watching documentary films
Travel

Naji Research and Development Company (2018 to now)

- The project manager of the government plan and budget system (in the field of operational budgeting, organization structure and the jobs of government employees)
- Supervisor of production, development and re-engineering of outsourced software systems of companies (in the field of control, management, feedback from projects outsourced to the private sector, such as people's social and cultural affairs systems, virtual training of government employees, the country's fuel system, the system of crimes and traffic violations and driving the country, police drug system)

Government organizations (2001 - 2018)

- Project manager of the basic information management system of comprehensive information systems (for two years, in the field of designing a system based on the Oracle database to consolidate the common basic information of other systems)
- Project manager of the government retired employees system (in the department of issuing pension orders, loans and facilities and other services related to retired state employees)
- General Sports System Project Manager of the Sports and Youth Organization (registering the information of athletes, names and sports talents and their records and domestic and international competitions and their results)
- Manager of the project of erasing electronic waste documents in the systems (in the field of erasing electronic waste documents based on systematically approved recipes, including photo, video waste information records)
- Cooperation in other government smart projects (designing a system for monitoring and monitoring the performance of government systems in the discussion of electronic government)
- Cooperation in the production of electronic government systems (in the field of serving the people by connecting the systems)
- Project manager, analyst and designer of the comprehensive system of the country's aviation, including 7 subsystems (control, maintenance, operation, fixed wing group, rotary wing group, air logistics and flight inspection)
- Analyst and designer and programmer of the system of the primary, regional and higher medical council of the government employees (filing and dealing with the problems of patients in the cities in a primary way and referring to the province for a regional consultation if necessary and finally referring to the capital for final treatment and Implementation of related processes and issuance of final decision for patients)
- Analyst and designer of the education and training system for government employees (establishing training courses and conducting exams and issuing valid certificates on the Internet)
- Analyst and designer and programmer of the personnel system of Tehran Tax Affairs Organization (recruitment, employment, promotion, punishments and incentives, organizational promotions, transfers, separation of employees from service, calculation of basic salary and retirement)
- Analyst and designer and programmer of Tehran's tax dispute resolution board system (creating a case for taxpayers and handling their complaints and finally issuing a decision for tax collection)
- Credit Cooperative System of Tehran Tax Affairs Organization (Definition of investment fund, agreement of subscription rights from members, payment of facilities, collection of installments, follow-up of arrears, and follow-up of offenders' case)
- Analyst and designer and programmer of the system for paying teaching fees for public university professors (defining professors and their classes, issuing teaching orders, paying fees, evaluating and recruiting new professors, etc.)
- Programmer of the information aggregation system of various databases (software design to convert databases into one with data modeling structure and detailed routines and functions as well as information transfer)
- Analyst and designer and programmer of the service companies system of Tehran municipality (recruitment of service personnel, training, implementation of cleaning mission in urban areas, supervision of the good implementation of urban cleaning, maintenance and repair of equipment, training, salaries and wages)

- Analyst and designer and programmer of the computer hardware information registration system (recording the specifications of each hardware device, allocation to the operator, relocation, maintenance, sale and purchase of new equipment)
- Analyst and designer of the administrative correspondence system (registration of correspondence inside and outside the organization, registration of file classes, follow-up of incoming and outgoing letters, referral of incoming letters to related persons, attachment of files to letters, delegation of authority, access control on each person's letters)

Skills

- Systems analyst and designer
 - ✓ Mastery of agile methodologies such as RUP(tool used by Rational Rose)
 - ✓ Mastery of UML modelling language(with Visio and Power Designer tools)
 - ✓ Mastery of BPMN(with Visio tool)
 - ✓ Mastery of the Scrum framework
 - ✓ Mastery of the production of technical documentation
- Programming Languages
 - ✓ Programming with the powerful Java language and related technologies
 - ✓ High proficiency in user interface design and system user interface design.
 - ✓ HTML/CSS Java Script// Bootstrap and...
 - ✓ Borland Delphi
- Advanced database programming
 - ✓ Oracle-PLSQL
 - ✓ MS SQL Server Script Programming
- Familiarity with project management and control software such as MSP
- Familiarity with the common software MS Office, Adobe Photoshop and...
- Basic knowledge of Linux, Git, and GitHub